

46 Hassan Basha Taher st. Bolkly, Alexandria, Egypt

🛮 (+20) 11-1771-0932 | 🖵 http://omarahmed.netlify.com | 🔀 omar.ahmed.oaaem@gmail.com | 🖸 omarking05 | 🛅 omarahmed0

"Be the change that you want to see in the world."

Summary.

Current Software Engineer in start-up company Botme. 3+ years of experience specializing in backend/frontend, web development. A super nerd who loves Terminal, Linux and enjoys to customize all of the development environment. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises.

Skills_

Programming PHP, Nodejs, Python, Javascript, Typescript

Front-End AngularX, ReactJS, ReactNative, Ionic2, HTML5, CSS, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap

Back-End RESTful API, Symfony, Expressis, Sailsis, SocketIO, JWT

Databases MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Redis

Languages Arabic, English

Work Experience _____

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Botme Giza, Egypt

Nov. 2017 - PRESENT Built the very first prototype of Botme which made Botme receive its initial funding.

- · Contributed in each aspect of Botme's core API, from designing and implementing the front-end at the very beginning until deploying the environment on AWS
- Devised Botme's chat-bot building system from scratch, to provide all Messenger's possible types of messages.
- Built Botme's commerce system to enable chat-bot builders to sell their products using chatbots in a very smooth, and tailored way.
- Developed an easy-to-use solution for Botme users to send targeted broadcasts to their chat bot users based on multiple factors (e.g. gender, first/last names, products, offers, or custom attributes).
- · Built and deployed overall service infrastructure utilizing several AWS stack(Including EC2, EB, Route 53, S3, IAM, Lambda) and implementing bash scripts for continues development, focusing on high-availability, fault tolerance, and auto-scaling.

Levari LLP Cairo, Egypt

FULL STACK DEVELOPER 2016 - Nov. 2017

- · Built Levari's website from scratch using Angularis and Sailsis, and migrated all the data from wordpress to the new stack.
- · Implemented Levari Client Platform to allow Levari's partners and client's to track lawyers progress.
- Built Levari Tracking App a hyprid mobile app used by Levari's lawyers to track their working hours daily.
- Migrated website hosting from Godaddy to AWS, and used CloudFlare CDN to optimize website speed.

Projects_

3alnet

FREELANCE PROJECT 2018

- 3alnet is a drop shipping ECommerce website using Sylius and Symfony.
- · It displays products from multiple websites and gives the customers the full ECommerce ability while having no Catalogs at all.
- Developed and customized Sylius to give the full ECommerce experience while all products were coming from another API.
- It displays products from multiple websites and gives the customers the full ECommerce ability while having no Catalogs at all.

A-Part

FREELANCE PROJECT 2017

- · A-Part is providing automotive spare parts and care maintenance services and is built on Oracle Commerce Cloud.
- Developed and customized the look and feel of the website.
- · Extended some OCC main functionalities (e.g. online payment, multi-criteria advanced search, Shipping integration) and to follow along with Oracle support and some of products' managers.

LazySquirrel

PERSONAL PROJECT 2018

· A simple tool in Python that helps developers start their every-day programs and development servers with a single command.

Car Rental System

Freelance Project

· Implemented API, and dashboard for a car rental booking App used to rent cars to users based on their locations.

Ground Cleaner

Personal Project 2016

• A NodeJs script developed to clean infected files caused by Ground.exe/autorun virus.

Restaurant Location-Based Advertising System

GRADUATION PROJECT 2016

· Web management system to automate restaurant orders and to provide location-based Ads using Beacons.

Education

Ain Shams University

Cairo, Egypt

2017

B.S. IN COMPUTER AND INFORMATION SCIENCE.

Mar. 2012 - Exp. Aug. 2016

Extracurricular Activity

OSCer (Open Source Community)

Cairo, Egypt

CORE MEMBER & HEAD OF IT AT 2015

2015 - Aug. 2016

- · Responsible for developing and maintaining community's website, and implementing networks during community sessions.
- · Organized various marketing and network activities to raise awareness of open source contributions/software.